<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dmitrii Storozhenko</title>
    <link>/authors/dmitrii-storozhenko/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dmitrii Storozhenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/dmitrii-storozhenko/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we need Large Language Models? Current state of Large Language Models, architecture, applications and limitations</title>
      <link>/post/2022-12-02-current-state-of-large-language-models-and-their-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-12-02-current-state-of-large-language-models-and-their-limitations/</guid>
      <description>Large language model is a machine learning model that is trained on a large amount of text data to generate human-like text. These models are typically used for natural language processing tasks, such as language translation, text summarization, and conversational AI/chatbots.
Why we need it? First of all, because they can capture the complex and nuanced patterns and structures of natural language, allowing them to generate more accurate and human-like text than smaller models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make AI sustainable? Best practices for CO2 tracking of AI/ML applications</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-27-how-to-make-ai-more-sustainable-carbon-emissions-tracking-and-reduction-for-ai-ml-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-27-how-to-make-ai-more-sustainable-carbon-emissions-tracking-and-reduction-for-ai-ml-applications/</guid>
      <description>What does sustainable AI/ML look like? How to measure carbon emissions, and at the same time, how to reduce energy consumption? These questions have become one of the hottest topics recently due to multiple factors, including all-time high energy prices, economic turmoil, and the echo of the COVID pandemic. Over the past few years, a growing number of papers highlighted the carbon emissions of machine learning (ML) workloads. While the standard software rarely provides this type of information, for now, we may already see some progress in the development area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrastive search and Leadership. What is in common between these words?</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-25-contrastive-search-leadership-and-transformers-what-is-in-common-between-these-three-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-25-contrastive-search-leadership-and-transformers-what-is-in-common-between-these-three-words/</guid>
      <description>Leadership part Leadership starts with a willingness to take risks. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you&amp;rsquo;re managing a team of five or hundreds of people. The point is to try new things that may be more successful or less successful. You should be willing to decide while dealing with uncertainty. This separates a leader from a jack of all trades and a master of none. Leaders know what they are good at and how to get the most out of their team and the people around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging SBERT and Cosine Similarity for finding clusters of similar emails</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-07-leveraging-sentence-bert-and-cosine-similarity-for-finding-clusters-of-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-07-leveraging-sentence-bert-and-cosine-similarity-for-finding-clusters-of-emails/</guid>
      <description>What is the difference between a phishing e-mail and an ordinary e-mail you receive from a colleague, friend, or even family member? One can say that the difference is in the way the message is presented to the recipient. This is a good point, but there are a few things to remember before making the distinction. There are many articles and papers about how to identify a phishing email. For instance:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the role of Artificial Intelligence in sustainable IT infrastructure and what are the challenges?</title>
      <link>/post/2022-08-16-how-artificial-intelligence-can-help-reduce-costs-from-it-infrastructure-to-industrial-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-08-16-how-artificial-intelligence-can-help-reduce-costs-from-it-infrastructure-to-industrial-production/</guid>
      <description>Google’s data centers around the world use about twice as much electricity as the city of San Francisco. At the same time, any Google data center is twice as energy efficient as a typical enterprise data center.C ompared with five years ago, Google now deliver around six times as much computing power with the same amount of electrical power. In 2020, the average annual Power Usage Effectiveness for the global fleet of data centers was 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief overview of the five top trends in Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-30-brief-overview-of-the-current-trends-in-artificial-intelligence-what-is-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-30-brief-overview-of-the-current-trends-in-artificial-intelligence-what-is-hot/</guid>
      <description>Explainable AI (XAI) One of the hottest topics in AI for 2022 is likely to be explainable AI (XAI), which involves developing AI systems that can explain their decisions and actions in a way that is understandable to humans. This is becoming increasingly important as AI systems are used in more critical and sensitive applications, such as healthcare, finance, and criminal justice.
Recent developments in XAI include the development of new methods and algorithms for explaining and interpreting AI models, such as model agnostic explanation methods and post-hoc explanation techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly detection algorithms. What is it? Which tools work better and how we can add weights and features to boost the accuracy with Extended Isolation Forest via R</title>
      <link>/post/anomaly-detection-algorithms-from-quantiles-to-extended-isolation-forest-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/anomaly-detection-algorithms-from-quantiles-to-extended-isolation-forest-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Anomaly detection plays a critical role in any business. For instance, imagine that your streaming service suddenly experiencing some technical problems but the support team has no idea about what&amp;rsquo;s going on, or you&amp;rsquo;re running some on-line mailorder, and transactions or conversion rate dropped without any obvious reason. For these types of events, we have to implement some sort of anomaly or changepoint detection systems.
Generally speaking, anomaly detection is the process of identifying unexpected items or events, which differ from normal ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the influence of a marketing treatment on a customer&#39;s purchase behavior. Uplift R packages overview</title>
      <link>/post/predicting-the-influence-of-a-marketing-treatment-on-a-customer-s-purchase-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/predicting-the-influence-of-a-marketing-treatment-on-a-customer-s-purchase-behavior/</guid>
      <description>Usually, the promotion of products occurs through communication with the client via various channels: push, SMS messages, etc. The formation of segments for promotion is solved by using machine learning. Today we will cover some of these approaches that solve the issue.
Based on Wikipedia - Uplift modeling, also known as incremental modeling, true lift modeling, or net modeling is a predictive modeling technique that directly models the incremental impact of a treatment (such as a direct marketing action) on an individual&amp;rsquo;s behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Netflix and YouTube built recommendation and personalization systems with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/how-netflix-and-youtube-builts-recommendation-and-personalization-systems-with-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-netflix-and-youtube-builts-recommendation-and-personalization-systems-with-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>While analyzing some of YouTube channels, we discovered that suggested videos take 60% of total views, and in this case, it could be useful to know how this type of algorithm works and how we could benefit from it.
So what should we expect in the future?
In the nearest future, we could expect that the share of suggested views may grow up to 80% (as it already turned out for Netflix).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glimpse on a MCI/MCI2 packages - market area models for retail and service locations</title>
      <link>/post/marketing-research-and-spatial-planning-in-retail-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/marketing-research-and-spatial-planning-in-retail-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Every time when we go to the grocery store or any other shop, we leave some data. On a micro scale this includes any checkout at a retail store. On a macro scale data is collected from groups of retailers. Generally, the point of sale data is collected by a business when some transaction happens.
This type of data could tell us a lot about consumer preferences and behaviour, but also we could imply market area models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking websites for hidden artifacts using R, with packages developed by top influencers in IT security</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-get-insights-from-a-security-point-of-view-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-get-insights-from-a-security-point-of-view-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Recently I came across some cybersecurity articles written by Mckinsey, but then I suddenly remembered one of the brilliant resources focused on R and cybersecurity research, DFIR, risk analysis, and much more. The person behind this resource is Bob Rudis* who wrote a book along with Jay Jacobs - &amp;ldquo;Data, Driven Security: Analysis, Visualization and Dashboards&amp;rdquo;. Bob Rudis is the Director of Enterprise Information Security &amp;amp; IT Risk Management at Liberty Mutual Insurance and was named one of the Top 25 Influencers in Information Security by Tripwire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get insights from Social Media using Machine Learning or why you shouldn&#39;t trust everything you see</title>
      <link>/post/social-media-using-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/social-media-using-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Preface Today I would like to share some insights based on influencer marketing and digital performance. Wikipedia says influencer marketing (a.k.a. influence marketing) is a form of social media marketing involving endorsements and product placement from influencers, people, and organizations who have a purported expert level of knowledge or social influence in their field. Influencer content may be framed as testimonial advertising; influencers play the role of a potential buyer or may be involved as third parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate marketing system simulator for different scenarios and channels</title>
      <link>/post/aggregate-marketing-system-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/aggregate-marketing-system-simulator/</guid>
      <description>Preface Running a business is like running a race, and in this term every item is important, so if you have powerful tools and bright minds, you will definitely get in a better position. Google are not only well-known for producing high quality products for users, but also for producing tools that helps us gain lot of insights from any type of data.
Today we&amp;rsquo;ll explore one of them for simulating aggregated marketing times series data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>