<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dmitrii Storozhenko</title>
    <link>/authors/hugo-authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dmitrii Storozhenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/hugo-authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the influence of a marketing treatment on a customer&#39;s purchase behavior. Uplift and tools4uplift R packages overview</title>
      <link>/post/predicting-the-influence-of-a-marketing-treatment-on-a-customer-s-purchase-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/predicting-the-influence-of-a-marketing-treatment-on-a-customer-s-purchase-behavior/</guid>
      <description>Usually, the promotion of products occurs through communication with the client via various channels: push, SMS messages, etc. The formation of segments for promotion is solved by using machine learning. Today we will cover some of these approaches that solve the issue.
Based on Wikipedia - Uplift modeling, also known as incremental modeling, true lift modeling, or net modeling is a predictive modeling technique that directly models the incremental impact of a treatment (such as a direct marketing action) on an individual&amp;rsquo;s behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Netflix and YouTube built recommendation and personalization systems with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/how-netflix-and-youtube-builts-recommendation-and-personalization-systems-with-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-netflix-and-youtube-builts-recommendation-and-personalization-systems-with-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>While analyzing some of YouTube channels, we discovered that suggested videos take 60% of total views, and in this case, it could be useful to know how this type of algorithm works and how we could benefit from it.
So what should we expect in the future?
In the nearest future, we could expect that the share of suggested views may grow up to 80% (as it already turned out for Netflix).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glimpse on a MCI/MCI2 packages - market area models for retail and service locations</title>
      <link>/post/marketing-research-and-spatial-planning-in-retail-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/marketing-research-and-spatial-planning-in-retail-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Every time when we go to the grocery store or any other shop, we leave some data. On a micro scale this includes any checkout at a retail store. On a macro scale data is collected from groups of retailers. Generally, the point of sale data is collected by a business when some transaction happens.
This type of data could tell us a lot about consumer preferences and behaviour, but also we could imply market area models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking websites for hidden artifacts using R, with packages developed by top influencers in IT security</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-get-insights-from-a-security-point-of-view-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-get-insights-from-a-security-point-of-view-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Recently I came across some cybersecurity articles written by Mckinsey, but then I suddenly remembered one of the brilliant resources focused on R and cybersecurity research, DFIR, risk analysis, and much more. The person behind this resource is Bob Rudis* who wrote a book along with Jay Jacobs - &amp;ldquo;Data, Driven Security: Analysis, Visualization and Dashboards&amp;rdquo;. Bob Rudis is the Director of Enterprise Information Security &amp;amp; IT Risk Management at Liberty Mutual Insurance and was named one of the Top 25 Influencers in Information Security by Tripwire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get insights from Social Media using Machine Learning or why you shouldn&#39;t trust everything you see</title>
      <link>/post/social-media-using-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/social-media-using-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Preface Today I would like to share some insights based on influencer marketing and digital performance. Wikipedia says influencer marketing (a.k.a. influence marketing) is a form of social media marketing involving endorsements and product placement from influencers, people, and organizations who have a purported expert level of knowledge or social influence in their field. Influencer content may be framed as testimonial advertising; influencers play the role of a potential buyer or may be involved as third parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate marketing system simulator for different scenarios and channels</title>
      <link>/post/aggregate-marketing-system-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/aggregate-marketing-system-simulator/</guid>
      <description>Preface Running a business is like running a race, and in this term every item is important, so if you have powerful tools and bright minds, you will definitely get in a better position. Google are not only well-known for producing high quality products for users, but also for producing tools that helps us gain lot of insights from any type of data.
Today we&amp;rsquo;ll explore one of them for simulating aggregated marketing times series data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On advertising performance evaluation with Data Science in mind</title>
      <link>/post/ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ads/</guid>
      <description>Preface Imagine that you are the CEO of the company, who clearly see that competitors are actively expanding in a market nevertheless tough times (and when was it different?). Your company produces a handy product or service. At the next meeting, together with the marketing and advertising department, you decided to launch an advertising company aimed to increase sales and brand awareness at the same time.
You have chosen specific types of advertising, deciding to go for both offline and online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houston, we have a problems, or when you should pay attention to the quality of analytical data</title>
      <link>/post/huston/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/huston/</guid>
      <description>This is an automated Google Translation from my russian version of website. Please visit later for better experience.
Preface Suppose your company has a long history and you are a vivid example of a modern leader who has already heard words such as Big Data, algorithms or artificial intelligence.
The company works like a clock, although of course there are moments of turbulence. The employees are all reliable, intelligent. But for some reason, the growth is not big enough, or dissapeared.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>